James Shepard Research and Draft of Colonial History of the Episcopal Church, Bristol, Connecticut
Connecticut Historical Society
James Shepard Research and Draft of Colonial History of the Episcopal Church, Bristol, Connecticut
before 1924
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Shepard, James
1.25 linear feet (2.5 boxes)
Biographical Sketch
James Shepard of New Britain, Connecticut, was a botanist, a historian, a genealogist and a long-time member of the Connecticut Historical Society. He published quite extensively in the areas of history and genealogy.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the unpublished manuscript for a history of the Episcopal parish in Bristol, Connecticut, during the colonial period, accompanied by several drafts, galleys, proofs, research notes, and correspondence written or compiled by James Shepard. The unpublished manuscript, with numerous edits and annotations, is in a binder. The drafts are arranged in page number or book number order. The correspondence, relating to his research or the publication of the book, is arranged chronologically and contains both incoming and outgoing letters.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is closed.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Shepard, James, 1838-1926.
Subjects
Bristol (Conn.) --Churches.
Contents:
- Papers
  - History of the Colonial Episcopal Parish of New Cambridge (Bristol), Connecticut (Box 1, Folder Vol. 1)
  - Draft of pages 1-242 (Box 1, Folder Vol. 2)
  - Draft of pages 243-385 (Box 1, Folder Vol. 3)
  - Draft of pages 386-454 (Box 1, Folder Vol. 4)
  - Draft of pages 485-598, Book No. 4 (Box 2, Folder Vol. 1)
  - Book No. 5 (Box 2, Folder Vol. 2)
  - Book No. 6 (Box 2, Folder Vol. 3)
  - Draft of “Records of the first Episcopal Church Established in Bristol” (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Draft of vestry records (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Information regarding publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Galleys of the book with multiple corrections and additions (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Printers proof of the book (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Research notes (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1911-1912 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 5-8)
  - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondence, 1916-1918 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Printed material (Box 3, Folder 13)